<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
<row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2011-01-11T20:45:08.070" Score="16" ViewCount="2244" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've got &lt;a href=&quot;http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/1558612467&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Native Tongue&lt;/a&gt; on my shelf, which is notable for having a language embedded in the story that can be spoken.  What else should I add to my reading list? I'm in particularly looking for books with developed languages, not just a few exotic place and character names added for flavor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; A language is well developed when it has a dictionary (or reasonably complete glossary) and reference grammar--or more likely--a few pages outlining how to string the words together. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(This question is copied verbatum from the Example Questions on Area 51)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is now community wiki, I'm sure there will be more than one question that could be marked as the answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="100" LastEditDate="2011-01-17T02:53:44.243" LastActivityDate="2011-03-20T13:02:02.600" Title="What science fiction novels have well developed alien languages?" Tags="&lt;novel&gt;&lt;languages&gt;" AnswerCount="8" CommentCount="6" FavoriteCount="3" ClosedDate="2011-01-20T16:28:59.467" CommunityOwnedDate="2011-01-11T20:54:27.723" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="232" CreationDate="2011-01-11T20:47:13.640" Score="18" ViewCount="495" Body="&lt;p&gt;In Lois McMaster Bujold's &lt;em&gt;Barrayar&lt;/em&gt; series, I can't recall any mention of Barrayar having a moon or of there being any other planets in its solar system.  Are there any references to them in the books?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="27" LastEditorUserId="70236" LastEditDate="2017-06-26T17:13:20.610" LastActivityDate="2017-06-26T17:13:20.610" Title="What other celestial bodies are in Barrayar's solar system?" Tags="&lt;vorkosigan-saga&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="2775" CreationDate="2011-01-11T20:49:52.980" Score="20" ViewCount="486" Body="&lt;p&gt;The plot of the TV series Total Recall 2070 implies that there are a variety of different types of androids.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt; Hume's partner, Ian Farve, is secretly a type of android called an 'Alpha'&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Almost all of the workers are called 'Deltas'.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does the series or any of the supporting materials mention any other types of androids?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="35" LastEditorUserId="770" LastEditDate="2013-10-01T17:50:10.107" LastActivityDate="2013-10-01T17:50:10.107" Title="Other than Alpha and Delta, were there any other types of androids in Total Recall 2070?" Tags="&lt;total-recall-2070&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="5" FavoriteCount="4" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2011-01-11T20:50:49.627" Score="11" Body="&lt;p&gt;I guess that depends on your definition of well developed.  These three are particularly well developed in my opinion:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dune.wikia.com/wiki/Fremen_language&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Fremen&lt;/a&gt;, from Dune&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sindarin&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Sindarin&lt;/a&gt;, from The Lord of the Rings (yes, I know, not sci-fi)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Klingon_language&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Klingon&lt;/a&gt;, from Star Trek&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastActivityDate="2011-01-11T20:50:49.627" CommentCount="4" CommunityOwnedDate="2011-01-11T20:54:27.723" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2011-01-11T20:52:46.753" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure of a book specifically that's heavy in klingon, but the klingon language itself is pretty much a full fledged language which was designed by an actual linguist. I don't know of any star trek books that make a lot of use of it, other then the klingon dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastActivityDate="2011-01-11T20:52:46.753" CommentCount="1" CommunityOwnedDate="2011-01-11T20:54:27.723" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="12" CreationDate="2011-01-11T20:53:41.560" Score="73" ViewCount="7232" Body="&lt;p&gt;In the Star Trek reboot (2009), since Nero and his crew travelled back in time, why didn't they just take off and warn their homeworld of its imminent destruction? The ship had warp drive, did it not?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="40" LastEditorUserId="7603" LastEditDate="2012-11-22T06:41:05.990" LastActivityDate="2018-02-06T05:24:52.567" Title="Why didn't Nero visit his homeworld to warn of its destruction?" Tags="&lt;star-trek&gt;&lt;star-trek-2009&gt;" AnswerCount="11" CommentCount="10" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="158763" CreationDate="2011-01-11T20:57:40.340" Score="37" ViewCount="105691" Body="&lt;p&gt;My googling says that the catastrophe in &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Road_%282009_film%29&quot;&gt;The Road&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is unexplained.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Given what we can see on-screen, can anyone come up with a better explanation for how the world got that way?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="19561" LastEditDate="2017-03-18T11:53:09.080" LastActivityDate="2017-05-04T20:47:26.893" Title="What was the catastrophe that happened in &quot;The Road&quot;?" Tags="&lt;the-road&gt;" AnswerCount="12" CommentCount="5" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="11" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="19" CreationDate="2011-01-11T21:02:44.203" Score="34" ViewCount="1189" Body="&lt;p&gt;I recently finished watching the great series &quot;Total Recall 2070&quot; that was based on Philip K. Dick's universe.  Philip K. Dick's absurdist blendings of philosophical problems with Sci-Fi has a unique flavor, so I'm looking for any TV or film works based on his writings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I've already seen &quot;Total Recall&quot; and &quot;Blade Runner&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="35" LastEditorUserId="976" LastEditDate="2012-01-14T19:05:27.743" LastActivityDate="2018-06-11T15:32:58.023" Title="What are the different works for Film and Television based on the works of Philip K. Dick?" Tags="&lt;movie&gt;&lt;tv&gt;&lt;philip-k-dick&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="4" FavoriteCount="8" />
  <row Id="12" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2011-01-11T21:03:30.583" Score="52" Body="&lt;p&gt;Nero was &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.memory-alpha.org/wiki/Nero#Arrival_in_the_23rd_century&quot;&gt;captured by the Klingons&lt;/a&gt; and tortured for almost 25 years. My guess is it drove him insane, leaving nothing but revenge in his mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastEditorDisplayName="user366" LastEditDate="2011-09-23T21:23:54.703" LastActivityDate="2011-09-23T21:23:54.703" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="14" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="8" CreationDate="2011-01-11T21:05:56.110" Score="16" Body="&lt;p&gt;As I remember, it was unexplained but had something to do with massive fire(s).  The movie somewhat shows this, but the book talks about grey skies, dead plant life, earthquakes, et cetera.  Since it happened suddenly, I'm kind of assuming some kind of natural planetary disaster, like a meteor or comet strike(s).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It's interesting to think about and discuss from a science point-of-view, but totally unnecessary for the human drama... other than the creation of a hostile environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Great book, &lt;em&gt;in my opinion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="9" LastEditDate="2012-09-15T20:34:57.123" LastActivityDate="2012-09-15T20:34:57.123" CommentCount="4" />
</posts>
  
